Pavithra Ramu

HR RECRUITER

Details

Chennai

India

9941622383

pavithra.ramu@gmail.com

Skills

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Communication Skills

Knowledge of MS Office

Microsoft Office

Social Media Recruiting Tools

Hobbies

Listening Music and Social Media

Languages

Tamil

English

Telugu

Profile

Experienced and self-motivated Human Resources Professional with two years of industry experience administering policies and procedures in the Human Resources Department of a fast-moving technology company. Bringing forth a proven track record of successfully managing Human Resource efforts and serving as a crucial pillar of support for HR teams and employees.

Employment History

HR Co-Ordinator, Aachi Groups of Company Pvt Ltd, Annanagar, Chennai

AUGUST 2020 — JANUARY 2023

- Assisted in maintaining all hard copy files for the HR department.
- Participating in the hiring process, Handing over employment contracts
- Preparing a detailed report of all HR activities, assisting <u>Campus Recruiter</u> in conducting campus interviews
- Recorded and reported employee issues, and brought them to Senior HRmembers when necessary.
- Preparing interview questions as per the designation.
- Developing reports for interviews conducted and other related things.
- Collaborated with the head of HR to meet and exceed all initiatives.
- Interview job candidates via calls and conduct on-site interviews.
- Coordinate with the management and corporate recruiters to find out the details of staffing requirements.
- Assist with all internal and external HR related inquiries or requests.
- Provide HR support to new hire on-boarding process
- Screen resumes and job application forms.
- Analytical skills to monitor progress of an undertaking and identify areas needing adjustment or improvement
- Arrange venues and schedules for meetings between all of the individuals who will be contributing to a tasks.

Customer Service Executive, Teleperformance Global Service, Chennai

NOVEMBER 2018 — APRIL 2020

- Helped to increase customer return rates by providing excellent customer service at all times.
- Provided top of the line customer service to all airport patrons.
- Worked with Customer Service and Product Development departments to enhance overall customer experience.
- Merchant Establishment (ME) for Shopping swiping machine.
- Provided excellent customer service and achieved a high rate of client satisfaction and retention.
- Redirected calls as needed and worked with my supervisor to address any outstanding issues or concerns.
- Kept records, calendars, and company information accessible.
- Keep up-to-date with the latest HR trends and best practices.
- Willingness to manage multiple tasks at once and adhere to guidelines, budgets, and deadlines

HR and Administrative Officer, Headway Properties Pvt Ltd, Annanagar, Chennai

FEBRUARY 2006 - NOVEMBER 2009

- Performed a variety of administrative duties, including answering phones, taking and delivering messages, writing memos, making copies, faxing documents, and greeting visitors.
- Served as an assistant to all administrative personnel and acted as a first point of contact for visitors and customers.
- Helped to plan and implement new HR policies, procedures, and standards.
- Remained flexible, adaptable, and punctual.
- Prepare reports and presentations on HR-related metrics like total number of hires by department
- Managing House Keeping, Purchasing, Stationeries, EB, Office Rental and Various services.
- Develop training and onboarding material

Courses:

Tally ERP, National Institute Of Technical Training

DECEMBER 2004 - MARCH 2005

Software Testing, Aimore Technology

AUGUST 2022 — DECEMBER 2022

Education

Board, Sethu Baskara Matric Hr Sec School, Chennai

JUNE 1999 — APRIL 2000

S.A.Polytechnic College, Diploma in Computer Technology, Poonamalle, Chennai

JUNE 2001 — APRIL 2003

Kalinga University, Bachelor of Computer Application, Raipur

JUNE 2014 - MAY 2017

Kalinga University, MBA HR, Raipur

JUNE 2017 - MAY 2019

Personal Details:

Gender : Female

Date Of Birth : 22/April/1986

Address : Thendral Nagar, West Balaji Nagar,

Kallikuppam, Ambattur, Chennai- 600053